Indiana History mss., 1725-1973 LMC 1544 LMC 1544
Lilly Library
- Indiana History
  - Performance bond, pay to Governor Jennings, 1819 (Box 1)
  - Mason, Daniel and Price, David, Brookville, Indiana deed of trust, 7 Oct. 1820 (Box 1)
  - Washington County, Salem, Indiana; deed for land sold for tax, 13 Nov. 1820 (Box 1)
  - Lindley, Ann, daughter of Jonathan Lindley, founder of Paoli, Indiana. Arithmetic sumbook., 1821, Jan. 11-1824, Jan. 10 -; Autograph Document Signed 58 p. 33 cm. (Box 1)
    Pp. 1-2, 9-10 and part of pp. 3-4 missing; pp. 29-30 torn.
    Arithmetic sum-book, pp. 3-44
    Penmanship exercises, pp. 45-48, 57
    Poetry, pp. 49-56, 58.
    Part of a New Albany, Ind.[?] newspaper of October, 1820 pasted inside cover.
    Gift. 1949
  - McCarty, Jonathan, early seal, 23 Mar. 1821 (Box 1)
  - Tipton, John, 1786-1839, soldier, U.S. Senator. Journal of John Tipton, commissioner on the part of the state of Indiana, appointed under act of the General Assembly, approved January 8, 1821, viz: "An act providing for running and marking the line dividing the states of Indiana and Illinois.", 1821, May 15-July 30 -; Document Signed 45 p. 26 cm.; genreform: blueprint. (Box 1)
    Original in Tipton Collection, Indiana State Library, Indianapolis, Indiana.
    Gift. 1922
  - Monroe, James, 1758-1831, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in District of Vincennes, state of Indiana to Philip Sumner of Gibson County, Indiana., 1821, Aug. 20 -; Document Signed 1 p.; folio; 25 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Countersigned: Josiah Meigs, Commissioner of The General land office.
    Gift. 1955
  - Campbell, William, petition for tavern permit, 20 Nov. 1822 (Box 1)
  - Bromfield, Stanther Promissory notes., 1822, Nov.21-1869, Jan. 1 -; 15 items. 6-10 cm. (Box 1)
    The signature, Stanther Bromfield, has been torn away from each note.
    Accompanied by letter of presentation, dated Winchester, May 10, 1935 and signed: India Bromfield.
    Gift. 1941
  - Hendricks, William, 1782-1850, governor of Indiana. Corydon. Commission to Joel D. Thomasson as justice of the peace for Floyd County., 1823, Apr. 17 -; Document Signed 3 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
  - Rush County, Rushville, Indiana; warrant with seal for the arrest of Joseph Looney, 21 Aug. 1823 (Box 1)
  - Montgomery County, Ind. Treasurer. County journal., 1823, Nov. 11-1841, Dec. 7 -; Autograph Document 163 p. 31 cm. (Bound 3)
    Purchase. 1936
  - Monroe, James, 1758-1831, pres. U.S. Washinton D.C. Grant of land in district of Brookville, state of Indiana, to James Moreman, of Randolph County, Indiana., 1824, Jan. 10 -; Document Signed 1 p.; folio.; 24 x 39 cm. (Box 5)
    Countersigned: George Graham, commissioner of General Land Office.
    Gift. Source and date unknown.
  - Owen, Robert, 1771-1858, social reformer. London. To William Rathbone, Liverpool. Plans to sail to America about October 1; inquires about packets sailing about that time., 1824, Sept. 3 -; Autograph Letter Signed 3 p. 23 cm. (Box 1)
    Purchase. 1959
  - Merrill, Samuel, 1792-1855, Indiana state treasurer. To Stephen C. Stevens, Speaker of the House of Representatives. List of expenses "incurred and paid for Removing the Records public property & c from Corydon to Indianapolis.", 1824 -; Photostat of Autograph Document 1 p. 29 cm. (Box 1)
    Accompanied by receipt from Carter Likens to Samuel Merrill, December 20, 1824, for $9.50 for carrying the law library to Indianapolis from Corydon. Attested by William H. Lilly. (Photostat of Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 10 cm.)
  - Jennings, Jonathan, 1784-1834, governor of Indiana. New Charleston. To John Kennedy Graham, New Albany, Floyd County, Indiana. Requesting his comments on "the Report of Engineers in relation to a 'Western Armory' " as far as "it relates to the opposite sides of the falls of Ohio;" asks his support of James M. Ross of Indianapolis who contemplates being a candidate for a clerkship., 1825, Sept. 17 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 22 cm.; genreform: photostats. (Box 1)
    Photostat from original in the possession of Mrs. Minnie Graham Zapp, New Albany, Indiana. Printed in Indiana Magazine of History. XXXIX; 294-95, Sept. 1943.
  - Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land "in the District of Jeffersonville and State of Indiana" to Thomas Charlton of Switzerland County, Indiana., 1826, May 26 -; Document Signed 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 38 cm. (Box 5)
    Countersigned by George Graham, commissioner of the General land office.
    Accompanied by transcript and covering letter from Orlando C. Charlton, Dallas, Texas, December 14, 1915, to the Librarian, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
    Gift. 1931
  - Peleg, Lewis, fl. 1830, New Providence, Clark County, Indiana. To James Gere and Eneas Morgan, Groton, Mass. Deal with family and local news, farming and prices., 1827, Sept. 8 - 1930, Mar. 28 -; 2 Autograph Letters Signed, 2 items, 6 p. 31-33 cm. (Box 1)
    Accompanied by typewritten transcripts.
  - Jackson County & Decatur County printed deed, 19 Feb. 1828 (Box 1)
  - Ray, James Brown, 1794-1848, governor of Indiana. Indianapolis. Commission to William Williams as justice of the peace for Floyd County., 1828, June 28 -; Printed form filled out in ms. 2 p.; 24 x 39 cm. (Box 1)
    Gift. Source unknown. 1946-1947
  - Second Prairie Creek Church, Vigo County, Indiana. Record book., 1828, Aug. 1-1875, June 6 -; Autograph Document 252 p. 19 cm. (Bound 4)
    Bound.
    In ink and pencil.
    Gift. 1965
  - Jones, Isaac E., Richmond, Ind. To his cousin, Jonah D. Thomas, Springboro, Ohio. Deals with church difficulties., 1829, Jan. 24 -; Autograph Letter Signed 3 p. 20 cm. (Box 1)
  - Rush County marriage consent letter, 27 Feb. 1829 (Box 1)
  - Yeager, John, Jr. and Yeager, Margaret, Vermillion County, Indiana. To John Yeager, Sr. Head of Greenbrier, Pocahontas County, Va. Description of country., 1829, Mar. 8 -; Autograph Letter Signed 3 p. 26 cm.; genreform: photostat. (Box 1)
    Photostat of the original in the possession of Mrs. Genevive Yeager Thompson, Athens, West Virginia.
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Crawfordsville, Ind., to Tolaver Larsh, of Montgomery County, Ind., 1829, Apr. 2 -; Document Signed 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Gift. 1958
  - Edwards, James L., fl. 1850, army officer, pension officer. To William Hendricks, U.S. Senate. Refers to the pension certificate for John Cheshire., 1829, Dec. 31 -; Letter Signed 1 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
  - Minute book of public schools in congressional township 13, range 7, east, in Shelby County, Indiana., 1829-1852 -; Autograph Document Signed 148 p. 34 cm. (Bound 5)
    Gift. 1963
  - Ledger of public land sold from Indianapolis., 1830, Jan. 1-1831, June 30 -; Autograph Document 119 p. 33 cm. (Bound 6)
    Purchase. 1942
  - Agreement between James Hunnicutt and George King, both of Warren County, Ohio, by which Hunnicutt accepts land in Clinton County, Indiana, in partial payment for merchandise furnished to King., 1830, July 19 -; Document Signed 2 p. 32 cm. (Box 1)
    Attested by Henry King, Jr., and Joshua Bailey.
  - Morrison, Catherine (Morris), 1812-1887. The Single Rule of Three [and other mathematical problems]., 1830, Sept. 14-1831, Sept. 6 -; Autograph Document 129 pp. 25.5 cm. Bound. (Bound 7)
    Cover wrapped in brown and white cloth.
    First leaf missing.
    Written in fine copperplate hand.
    Other problems include: Insurance, Commission and Brokage, Vulgar Fractions, Domestic and Foreign Exchange, The Cube Root, Duodecimals, Life Annuities, Alligation, Tonnage of Ships.
    Note in pencil about Catherine Morris on first page.
    Accompanied by genealogical account of the Ancestors of Catherine Morris in America.
    Gift. 1981
  - Jackson County [Brownstown] manuscript Indiana deed, signed William E. Ewing, 3 Feb. 1831 (Box 1)
  - Wright, Ann, fl. 1831, Richmond, Ind. To her cousin, Lydia Thomas, Springborough, Warren County, Ohio. Local News., 1831, Aug. 2 -; Autograph Letter Signed 3 p. 20 cm. (Box 1)
  - Palmers Prairie, Sullivan County, Indiana, Christian church on Busseron Creek. Minute book, 1831-1903., Autograph Document 46 p. 19 cm.; genreform: photostat. (Box 1)
    Consists of lists of members only.
    Photostat from the original in the possession of the church.
    Edited by Mrs. Chloe (Siner) Morgan and published in Indiana Magazine of History, XLVII; p. 111-127, March 1951.
  - Rogers, Andrew. Estate inventory., 31 Aug. 1833 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Board of Directors of the Lawrenceburgh and Indianapolis Railroad Co., 1832, Feb. 23 - 1839, Sept. 2 (Bound 8)
  - Snapp, John F., miller and dealer in lumber. Daybook., 1832, June 8-1835, July 25 -; Autograph Document Signed 160 p. 37 cm. (Bound 9)
  - Christian College, New Albany, Ind. Diploma., 1833, Mar. 5 -; Document Signed 1 p. 53 cm.; copy. (Box 7)
    Photograph.
    Signed by John Cook Bennett, Chancellor; Chauncey F. Perkings, Dean; and John L. Riddell, Registrar & Bursar.
    "Under John Cook Bennett, its first president or chancellor, this diplomill began dispensing degrees to the highest bidders, a practice which it continued for a number of years, although the institution actually never did go into legitimate operation."
    M.E. Pickard and R.C. Buley The Midwest Pioneer: His Ills, Cures & Doctors… Crawfordsville, Indiana, Banta, 1945, p. 141.
    Framed.
    Gift. 1959
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, pres. U.S. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Indianapolis, Ind., to David Henricks of Shelby County, Indiana., 1833, Apr. 17 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Signed: "Andrew Jackson by Andrew Jackson Donelson Sec'y"
    Countersigned: Elijah Hayward, Commissioner of the General land office. Accompanied by record of survey of "South West corner of section 28 in Township 13 of R4 East" for David Henricks & William Morris. Signed: Joseph B. Nickel.
    Gift. 1950
  - Rodgers, Andrew. Estate inventory, 31 Aug. 1833 (Box 1)
  - Scott Township, Vanderburgh County, Indiana. Citizens, Minutes of a Meeting of the Inhabitants of Scott Township held on … the 30th Sept., 1833 … in Saundersville for the purpose of taking into consideration the propriety and necessity of erecting a building to be appropriated for the purpose of a meeting house, school, or a place in which can be transacted the public business of the township., 1833, Sept. 30-Oct. 29 -; Autograph Document Signed 4 p. 24 cm.; Verifax copy. (Box 1)
    Signed: Saunders Hornbrook, president.
    Accompanied by a resolution of the building committee, Oct. 29, 1833. Autograph Document 1 p. 32 cm.
    Accompanied by typescript.
    Verifax copy made at Indiana University Library from the original in the possession of Mrs. Madelaine Warren Guthrie, Evansville, Indiana. 1958
  - Custis, William H. B., 1814-, state legislator, et al. Bloomington, Indiana. To Albert Smith White. "You have been unanimously elected an honorary member of the Athenian Society of Indiana College.", 1833, Dec. 22 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
    Accompanied by announcement of Lafayette Female Seminary, Lafayette, Indiana.
    Gift. 1966
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Fort Wayne, Ind., to James Moorman, of Wayne County, Indiana., 1834, Aug. 5 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Andrew Jackson By Andrew Jackson Donelson Secy."
    Countersigned: Elijah Hayword, commissioner of the General land office.
  - Holcomb, Oliver & Co., collection agents. Lists of notes for collection in southwestern Indiana; southeastern Illinois, and northwestern Kentucky; memoranda of notes given to James St. C. Stuart and Edwin Adams, collection agents to collect; accounts, including records of sales of clocks., 1835, Sept. 21-1839, Mar. 2 -; Autograph Document 158 p. 22 cm. (Bound 10)
    Purchase. 1947
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to David Arnold of Harrison County, Ind., 1835, Sept. 25 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Andrew Jackson By Andrew Jackson Donelson Secty."
    Countersigned: Ethan Allen Brown, commissioner of the General land office.
    Gift. 1933
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Samuel Stanfield, of Jackson County, Ind., 1835, Sept. 25 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Andrew Jackson By Andrew Jackson Donelson Secy"
  - Friends, Society of Indiana. Account book of Indiana Yearly Meeting of Friends., 1835, Sept. 30-1841, Aug. 14 -; Autograph Document 8 p. 20 cm. (Box 1)
    Includes accounts of the fund for the use of the Committee on the concerns of the people of colour, Jan. 24, 1836-Sept. 23, 1841.
  - Gibson County, Ind. Tax book., 1835 -; Document 156 p. 18 cm. (Bound 11)
    Includes also a record of brick sold, Sept. 23, 1844-Feb. 12, 1845 by the brick yard of Joseph Kirkman in Princeton, Ind.
    Gift of Lawrence Wheeler. Donor's letter in pocket in back of book.
    Gift. 1944
  - Diary of travel from Goshen, Indiana, crossing the Tippecanoe River and the Eel River, 1836, Feb. 9-14 -; Autograph Document 19 p. 16.7 cm. (Box 1)
    Author is a "young lady"
    Beginning words: Started from Goshen. Not as when we left our native place, …
    In brown ink.
    Accompanied by pencil transcript.
    Gift. 1996
  - Marion County land indenture, 2 June 1836 (Box 1)
  - Parke County manuscript deed, 31 Dec. 1836 (Box 1)
  - Lawrence County petition for ferry access across White River, 218 signatures, 3 Jan 1837 (Box 1)
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washinton D.C. Grant of land in district of land subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to James Cousens, of Jackson County, Ind., 1837, Mar. 15 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Martin Van Buren By Abraham Van Buren Secy."
    Countersigned: H. M. Garland, recorder of the General land office.
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washinton D.C. Grant of land to Nathan Pearson., 1837, Mar. 15 -; Document 1 p. (Folio 1)
  - Barlow, Ames & Co., merchants, tailors, and dealers in lumber, Princeton, Ind. Account book for tailoring and merchandising business., 1837, May 11-1838, July 7 -; Autograph Document Signed 157 p. 20 cm. (Bound 12)
    One bill laid in.
  - Posey County to Gibson County, Indiana; summons, 17 May 1837 (Box 1)
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Deed of land in Indiana to James Moorman of Wayne County, Ind., 1837, Aug. 1 -; 1 p. folio. 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature is: "Martin Van Buren by A. Van Buren Sec'y"
    Countersigned: Joseph S. Wilson, acting recorder of the General land offce.
    Gift. Source unknown. 1947
  - Marion County indenture, 10 Aug. 1837 (Box 1)
  - Washington County, Salem, Indiana; indenture of land, 27 Dec. 1837 (Box 1)
  - Kellogg, Miner Kilbourne, 1814-1889, artist. Private journal., 1838, Jan. 1 -; Xerox copy of Autograph Document Signed 23 p. 36 cm. (Box 1)
    Original in the Indiana Historical Society Library, Indianapolis, Indiana.
    Gift. 1968
  - Weaver, Joseph, Jr. Chester, Delaware County, Pa. To Squire Hulley, Madison, Jefferson County, Ind. Concerns the settlement of the Bottomley estate., 1838, Jan. 15 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 32 cm. (Box 1)
    Cover included.
  - An Act to Incorporate the City of Logansport, Indiana., 1838, Feb. 17 -; Autograph Document Signed 20 leaves. 30 cm. (Box 1)
    This contemporary copy of the original city charter of Logansport was made for Jordan Vigus, 1792-1860, first mayor of the city, and signed by David Wallace, 1799-1859, governor of Indiana, Thomas Jefferson Evans, -1840, speaker of the House, and Amaziah Morgan, president of the Senate, pro tem.
    Purchase. 1974
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of land subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Bevarly Richardson of Jackson County, Ind., 1838, Aug. 1 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 26 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Martin Van Buren By Martin Van Buren, Jr. Secy."
    Countersigned: Joseph S. Wilson, acting recorder of the General land office.
  - Crumbaugh, Fred. Madison, Ind. To James H. Johnson, Cincinnati, Ohio. Concerns misunderstandings arising from their earlier correspondence., 1838, Dec. 2 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 p. 29 cm. (Box 1)
  - Reports concerning the construction of a free bridge across Tanners Creek in Dearborn Co., 1838 (Box 1)
    Purchased. Paul H. North, Jr., Books & Art, 81 Bullitt Park Place, Columbus, Ohio 43209.
  - Owen County, indenture, 13 Mar. 1839 (Box 1)
  - Barlow, Ames and Co., merchants, tailors, and dealers in lumber. Memorandum book for lumbering business, time sheets of employees, tables of measures, etc., 1839, July-1844, Mar. -; Autograph Document 282 p. 20 cm. (Box 1)
    Pp. 23, 50, 57, 91 and 92 contain listings of materials for flatboats. Laid in: 1) Holcomb, Oliver, New Harmondy, Ind. To Barlow, Ames & Co., Princeton, Ind., Mar. 1, 1839. 2) Barlow, John. Bill to Gibson County, Ind., for material for courthouse.
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in district of land subject to sale at Vincennes, Ind., folio to Green Cunningham of Gibson County, Ind., 1839, Aug. 1 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Martin Van Buren By Martin Van Buren, Jr., Secy."
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres., U.S. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Squire Wilson of Martin County, Ind., 1839, Aug. 1 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 26 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Martin Van Buren By Martin Van Buren Secy"
    Countersigned: Joseph S. Wilson, acting recorder of the General land office adinterim.
    Purchase. 1951
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Two grants of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to David Arnold of Harrison County, Ind., 1839, Aug. 1 -; Document 2 p.; folio.; 25-26 x 41 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "Martin Van Buren By Martin Van Buren Jr., Secy"
    Countersigned by Joseph S. Wilson, acting recorder of the General land office.
  - Holcomb, Oliver & Co., collection agents. Accounts with collection agents., 1839, Sept. 24-1845, May 30 -; Autograph Document 108 p. 20 cm. (Box 1)
    Principally accounts of James Finch, collection agent in southwestern Indiana, southeastern Illinois and northwestern Kentucky.
  - Marion County indenture, 27 Sept. 1839 (Box 1)
  - Methodist Protestant Church. Conferences. Indiana. Minutes of quarterly conferences of the White River Circuit., 1839, Nov. 16-1855, May 25 -; Document 192 p. 31 cm. (Bound 13)
    Includes also Register of marriages, June 25, 1840-Apr. 28, 1853; register of baptisms, May 12, 1841-Nov. 15, 1852; list of male members over the age of 21 years on the White River Circuit, 1844.
    Many pages missing.
  - Kern, David G., businessman of Milton, Indiana, and others. Select & original poetry., 1839-1842 -; Autograph Document 70 p. 19 cm. (Box 1)
    Accompanied by an insurance receipt and an advertisement for Kern's store.
    Purchase. 1962
  - Gibson County, Princeton, Indiana; summons, 30 Jan. 1840 (Box 1)
    Summons for John Crowder, [Martin or Milton] Harger, and [Charles or Carlos] Lovejoy
  - Harrison County, U.S. citizenship intent of a German, 23 June 1840 (Box 1)
  - Mote, David, Wayne County, Ind. To David Jones, Friends establishment, Indiana territory. Refers to the death of David Jones' father., 1840, Oct. 4 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 32 cm. (Box 1)
  - Owen County legal document, 3 Mar. 1841 (Box 1)
    Names mentioned: William W. Farley; Findley B. Johnson; Samuel and Catharine Purkiser (nee Graves); Catharine's mother, Mary Graves of Morgan County; John Cobell, Mary's father-in-law; Thomas C. Johnson; David M'Donald.
  - Smith, Oliver Hampton, 1794-1859, U.S. Senator. Indianapolis, Ind. To Lewis Jacob Cist. "I will hand it [Cist's letter] to such of the persons named by you as I may see.", 1841, Apr. 12 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
  - Smith, Thomas Lacey, to Levi Lewis in Delaware County, PA, 22 Jan. 1842; 10 Jul. 1842; 6 Sep. 1843 (Box 1)
    Three autograph letters variously signed, all from Thomas Lacey Smith to Levi Lewis
    Purchased from Halvor Americana of Clarendon Hills, IL, 17 Apr. 2012, along with other items for $445
  - Jackson County Brownstown, Indiana constable's bond of Sparrel Carter for $1,000 conditional upon his doing his duty as constable, 7 Apr. 1842 (Box 1)
  - Simpson, Matthew, 1811-1884, Bishop, Greencastle, Ind. To Thomas S. Hitt, Mount Morris, Ogle County, Ill. Recommending Charles H. Titus as principal of his institution., 1842, May 7 -; Autograph Letter Signed, 22 items, 2 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
    Note on back: "Copy of a letter from Pres. Simpson to T. S. Hitt."
    Included in same folder are 21 documents, dated Oct. 23, 1835- July 27, 1844, relating to Charles H. Titus, including licenses as a preacher in the Methodist Episcopal Church in the Portland district, Maine conference, and the Newcastle district, Indiana conference, and recommendations as a teacher and preacher. Autograph Document Signed 21 p. 6-25 cm.
  - Fletcher, Calvin, 1798-1966 [sic], lawyer, banker. Indianapolis, Indiana To Douglass Luce, Urbana, Ohio. Refers to the financial settlement with William Ward and Pain [?] in 1830., 1842, Sept. 28 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 p. 24 cm. (Box 1)
  - Collins, E.G. Ledger., 1842-1847 (Bound 14)
  - New Salem, Ind. Regular Baptist Church of Jesus Christ. Minutes., 1843, Jan. 21-1858, July 24 -; Autograph Document, 2 items, 2 v. 30-33 cm. (Bound 15)
    [v. 1] January 21, 1843-August 28, 1852
    [v. 2] June 26, 1852-July 24, 1858.
  - Tyler, John, 1790-1862, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Joel McCory of Jackson County, Ind., 1843, Apr. 10 -; Document 1 p.; 25 x 40 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "John Tyler By R. T. Tyler Sec'y."
    Countersigned: J. Williamson, recorder of the General land office.
  - Marion County, Madison and Indianapolis Railroad Company, indenture, 1 May 1843 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Theodore, journalist. Indianapolis, Ind. To John Serbie Watts, editor of the Bloomington Post Ind. Enclosing clipping from Indianapolis Sentinel concerning George Grundy Dunn, and asking whether Dunn made the remark attributed to him in regard to the Indiana Journal., 1843, June 20 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 31 cm. (Box 1)
  - Grover, O.H.P., fl. 1843, Winamac, Ind. To James Lasselle. Asking for date of the publication of a sale of a section of land., 1843, Aug. 6 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 24 cm. (Box 1)
  - Lathrop, James B. Lecture notes from classes given by Andrew Wylie at Ind. Univ., 1844-1845 -; 1 manuscript notebook. 31 cm. Assorted newspaper clippings. (Box 1)
  - Indiana. State Bank. Ft. Wayne Branch. Minute Book, Letter B., 1844, July 2-1858, Dec. 23 -; Autograph Document 462 pp. 41 cm.; bound. (Bound 16)
    Minutes of the meetings signed by bank presidents:
    Samuel Hanna, 1844, July 2-1847, Oct. 26
    Allen Hamilton, 1847, Nov. 18-1858, Mar. 25
    Lott S. Bayless, 1858, Nov. 16-Dec. 23.
    Signature of Stephen B. Bond appears on Dec. 14, 1858, for an extensive financial transaction.
  - Methodist Episcopal Church. Conferences. Indiana. Minutes of the Indiana conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church., 1844, Sept. 25-1851, Oct. 15 -; Typed copy. [4], 227 [i.e. 242] p. 23 cm. (Bound 17)